Guide to the Leopold Haimson papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series XI: Writings by Others, 1934-1990s
  - Subseries XI.2: Academic and Professional Works, 1934-1990s
    - Bialer, Seweryn:
      - "Soviet-American conflict: from the past to the future," 1984 (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Binion, Rudolph. "Repeat performance: a psychohistorical study of Leopold III and Belgian neutrality," 1969 (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Boll, Friedhelm:
      - "Comparison internationale des vagues de greves 1889-1914" (Box 149, Folder 6)
      - "Problem des internationalen Vergleichs von Streikwellen" (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Bonnell, Viktoria. "Introduction to The Russian worker: life and work in tsarist society as seen by contemporaries" (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Brian, E. "K voprosu o politicheskoi i sotsial'noi identifikatsii rabochikh Rossii v kontse XIX-go - nachale XX-go vekov" and "Labor unrest in Imperial Russia during the First World War: a quantitative analysis and interpretation": see Haimon's writings
    - Brinton, Crane. "Political ideas of St. Just," 1934 (Box 149, Folder 8)
    - Brooks, Jeffrey. "Vekhi and the Vekhi dipute," 1973 (Box 149, Folder 8)
    - Brower, Daniel. "Russian cities in crisis: the urban population in the Civil War" (Box 149, Folder 9)
    - Brown, J."Rumania today," 1969 (Box 149, Folder 9)
    - Brzeski, Andrzej. "Poland as a catalyst of change in the communist economic system," 1971 (Box 149, Folder 10)
    - Brzezinski, Zbigniew:
      - "East-West relations after Czechoslovakia," 1969 (Box 149, Folder 10)
      - "Five years after Khrushchev," 1969 (Box 149, Folder 10)
      - "Half past Nixon," 1971 (Box 149, Folder 10)
      - "Victory of the Clerks: What Khrushchev's Ouster Means": see in Fall of Khrushchev (Box 149, Folder 3)
      - "U.S.-Soviet relations," 1973 (Box 149, Folder 10)
    - Burko, Faina. "Soviet Yiddish theatre in the twenties," 1978 (Box 149, Folder 11)
      (dissertation)
    - Bushkoff, Leonard. "Paul Miliukov. Political Memoirs, 1905-1917:" see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.3: Chronological--1969--Bushkoff (Box 9, Folder 3)
      (reprint of the book review published in Canadian Slavic Studies, II, No. 4: 576-580, Winter, 1968)
    - Chang, Parris. "Radicals and radical Ideology in China's cultural revolution," 1973 (Box 149, Folder 12)
    - Chase, William:
      - "Soviet data bank," 1986 (Box 149, Folder 13)
        (project proposal)
      - "Workers, society and the state: labor and life in Moscow, 1918-1929," 1984 (Box 149, Folder 14)
      - "Workers, society and the state: labor and life in Moscow, 1918-1929," 1984 (cont.) (Box 150, Folder 1-4)
    - Chermenskii, E.D.:
      - "E.N. Burdzhalov. Vtoraia russkaia revoliutsiia. Vosstanie v Petrograde. Izd-vo 'Nauka'. Moskva 1967," 1968, (typescript with holograph notes, signed) (Box 150, Folder 5)
      - "Zemsko-liberal'noe dvizhenie nakanune revoliutsii 1905-1907 gg.," 1965 (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Cherniavskii, Michael. "Old Belivers and the New Religion," 1966 (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Clive, Geoffrey. "Revolt of the masses by Jose Ortega y Gassett," 1974 (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Conner, Kimberly. Untitled (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Coquin, Francois-Xavier. "Echos de l'Affaire Dreyfus en Russie" (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Costas, Ilse. "Auswirkungen der Konzentration des Kapitals auf die Arbeiterklasse in Deutschland (1880-1914)," 1981 (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Cronin, James. "Politics, class structure, and the enduring weakness of British social democracy" (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Curtiss, John. "Peasant and the army," 1968 (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Czap, Peter, Jr.
      - "Eine zahlreiche familie - des bauern grosster reichthum". Leibeigenenhaushalte in Misino, Russland, 1814-1858," 1982 (Box 150, Folder 7)
      - "Perennial multiple family household, Mishino, Russia 1782-1858," 1982 (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Dallin, Alexander:
      - "Communist diversity: problems for Moscow and Washington," 1967 (Box 150, Folder 8)
      - "Political terror in the post-mobiliztion stage," 1970 (Box 150, Folder 8)
      - "Soviet foreign policy and domestic politics: a framework for analysis" (Box 150, Folder 8)
      - "Soviet Union and the Indochina conflict," 1970 (Box 150, Folder 8)
    - Daniels, Robert. "Fate and will in the Marxian philosophy of history," 1960 (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Davis, Robert. Essay (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Deak, Istvan. "Decline and fall of Habsburg Hungary, 1914-1918," 1971 (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Debreczeny, Paul. "Reception of Pushkin's poetic works in the 1820s a study of the critic's role," 1969 (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Denitch, Bogdan. "Notes on the relevance of Yugoslav self-management" (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Devlin, Kevin. "Communism in Israel," 1969 (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Dickenson, Connie. [Third Duma] (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - Draper, Theodore. "Five years of Castro's Cuba," 1964 (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - Durand, Michelle. "Greve: conflit structurel, systeme de relations industrielles ou facteur de changement social," 1979 (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Eckstein, Harry. "Crisis in modern Norwegian history," 1968 (Box 150, Folder 12)
    - Economakis, Evel. "Marriage in Moscow, 1864-1917 an analysis of the main characteristics of marriage in Moscow, as reflected in the Marriage Register of all Houses of Worship in that city" (Box 150, Folder 12)
    - Edwards, P.K. "Strikes in the United States, 1881-1974" (Box 150, Folder 12)
    - Elwood, Ralph
      - "RSDRP in Ekaterinoslaw: profile od an underground organization, 1907-14," 1965 (Box 150, Folder 13)
      - "Trotsky's questionnaire," 1970 (Box 150, Folder 13)
    - Emmons, Terence. "Russian landed gentry and politics," 1973 (Box 150, Folder 13)
    - Erlich, Alexander:
      - "Economic reform in communist countries," 1967 (Box 151, Folder 1)
      - "Hamlet without the Prince of Denmark," 1973 (Box 151, Folder 1)
      - "National economic planning," 1967 (Box 151, Folder 1)
      - "Notes on Marxian model of capital accumulation," 1967 (Box 151, Folder 1)
      - "Soviet industrialization debate, 1924-1928," 1960 (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Esper, Thomas:
      - "Impact of serfdom on the Russian metallurgical industry in the nineteenth century" (Box 151, Folder 2)
      - "Incomes of Russian serf inronworkers in the nineteenth century" (Box 151, Folder 2)
      - "Odnodvortsy and the Russian nobility" (Box 151, Folder 3)
      - "Replacement of the Longbow by firearms in the English army," 1965 (Box 151, Folder 3)
      - "Russia and the Baltic 1494-1558," 1966 (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - Fallows, Thomas:
      - "Boris Grigor'evich Litvak. Russkaia derevnia v reforme 1861 goda. Chernozemnyi tsentr, 1861-1895" (Box 151, Folder 4)
      - "Notes on the role of third element radicalism in Zemstvo politics" (Box 151, Folder 4)
    - Field, Daniel:
      - "Ivan Dmitrievich Koval'chenko. Russkoe krepostnoe krest'ianstvo v pervoi polovine XIX v." (Box 151, Folder 5)
      - "P.V.Dolgorukov's emigration from Russia" (Box 151, Folder 5)
      - "Peasants and propagandists in the Russian movement to the people of 1874," 1986 (Box 151, Folder 5)
      - "Polarization of peasant households in pre-Revolutionary Russia: Zemstvo censuses and problems of measurement," 1984 (Box 151, Folder 6)
      - "Stratification and the Russian peasant commune: a statistical inquiry," 1986 (Box 151, Folder 6)
    - Fine, John. "Was the Bosnian banate subjected to Hungary in the second half of the thirteenth century?" 1969 (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Focas, Spiridon. "Bessarabia in the political order of Southeast Europe in the 19th century," 1968 (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Foust, Cliffordl. "Russia'a Peking caravan, 1689-1762," 1968 (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Freidin, Gregory. "To the memory of my Russian childhood," 1980 (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Frierson, Cathy. "Crime and punishment in the Russian village: rural concept of criminality at the end of the nineteenth century," 1986 (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Galili, Ziva. "Menshevik leaders of the Soviets in 1917 social realities and political strategies in the Russian revolution," 1986 (Box 151, Folder 8-10)
    - Gerschenkron, Alexander:
      - "Criticism from afar: a reply," [1971] (Box 152, Folder 1)
      - "Manufactured monument?" 1966 (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - Getty, J.: see Chase, William
    - Gillis, John. "Historical sequences of the political development of Germany," 1968 (Box 152, Folder 2)
    - Gindin, I.F.:
      - "Modernisierungs und industrialisierungsprobleme und wie sie sich von 16.bis zum 20. Jahrundert gewandlet haben" (Box 152, Folder 2)
      - "Sotsial'no-ekonomicheskie itogi razvitiia rossiiskogo kapitalizma i predposylki revoliutsii v nashei strane," 1970 (Box 152, Folder 2)
      - "V.I.Lenin o sotsial'noj strukture i politicheskom stroe kapitalisticheskoi Rossii," 1969 (Box 152, Folder 2)
    - Glikman, Rose. "Russian factory woman, 1880-1914," 1977 (Box 152, Folder 3)
    - Graham, Loren. "Soviet perspectives on genetic engineering" (Box 152, Folder 3)
    - Grew, Raymond. Comments on papers by the Committee on Comparative Politics SSRC (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - Griffins, David. "Nikita Panin, Russian diplomacy, and the American Revolution," 1969 (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - Grimsted, Patricia. "Archives in the Soviet Union: their organization and the problem access," 1971 (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - Gurevitz, Baruch:
      - "Bolshevik Revolution and the foundation of the Jewish communist movement in Russia," 1976 (Box 152, Folder 5)
      - "Cas de communisme national en Union Sovietique le poale Zion, 1918-1928," 1973 (Box 152, Folder 5)
      - "Liquidation of the last independent party in the Soviet Union," 1976 (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - Guroff, Gregory. "Note on urban literacy in Russia, 1890-1914," 1971 (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - Haithcox, John. "Left wing uity and the Indian nationalist movement: M.N.Roy and the Congress Socialist Party," 1969 (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Hammer, Darrell. "Composition of the CPSU: some exploratory research" (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Harper, William. "University and democracy," 1970 (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Harrassowitz, Otto. "Slavistik osteuropaische geschichte," 1970 (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Harussi, Yael. "Gogol's Dead Souls: a reading," 1973 (Box 152, Folder 7)
      (doctoral theses)
    - Hasegawa, Tsuyoshi. "Crime and revolution in Petrograd, 1917," 1981 (Box 152, Folder 8)
    - Haupt, Georges:
      - "Commune comme symbole et comme exemple," 1972 (Box 152, Folder 8)
      - "Guerre et revolution chez Lenine," 1971 (Box 152, Folder 8)
      - "Histoire du bolchevisme," 1967 see Rosenberg, Arthur
    - Hazzard, John:
      - "Implementing in law Post-Keita Mali's retreat from "Scientific Socialism" (Box 152, Folder 8)
      - "Socializing Islamic law in Africa," 1973 (Box 152, Folder 8)
    - Hellie Richard:
      - "Functions of slavery in Muscovy," 1976 (Box 152, Folder 9)
      - "Merchant of Moscow 1580-1650. By Paul Bushkovitch. Book review," 1980 (Box 152, Folder 9)
      - "Muscovite slavery in comparative perspective," 1978 (Box 152, Folder 9)
      - "Slavery and the law in Muscovy," 1975 (Box 152, Folder 9)
      - "Structure of modern Russian history: toward a dynamic model," 1977 (Box 152, Folder 9)
      - "What happened? How did he get away with it? Ivan Grozny's paranoia and the problem of institutional restraints," 1984 (Box 152, Folder 9)
    - Herlihy, Patricia. "Death in Odessa: a study of population movements in a nineteenth-century city," 1978 (Box 152, Folder 10)
    - Herr, Richard. "Comments on the crises of political development with reference to the history of Spain," 1968 (Box 152, Folder 10)
    - Hogan, Heather:
      - "Origins of the scientific management movement in Russia," 1983 (Box 152, Folder 11)
      - "Problems of labor organization in the St. Petersburg metal working industry" (Box 152, Folder 11)
      - "Reorganization of work processes in the St. Petersburg metal-working industry, 1901-1914" (Box 152, Folder 12)
        (preliminary draft)
      - "Russian metal workers and their Union, the organization composition, and leadership of the St. Petersburg Metal Workers' Union, 1906-1914" (Box 152, Folder 12)
    - Hollander, Paul. "Leisure as an American and Soviet value," 1966 (Box 152, Folder 13)
    - Janos, Andrew. "Elites and the crises of development in backward societies: the case of Eastern Europe: 1848-1944," 1968 (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Jeu, Bernard. "Philosophie europeenne compare: au sujet d'un livre d'Alexis Ivanovitch Vvedenski," 1967, (reprint) (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Johns III, Sheridan. "Birth of non-white trade unionism in South Africa," 1967 (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Johnson, Gale; Kahan, Arcadius. "Soviet agricultural program: an evaluation of the 1965 goals," 1962 (Box 153, Folder 2)
    - Johnson, Mark S.:
      - "Issues in contemporary Soviet Education," 1991 (Box 153, Folder 3)
      - "Russian educators, the Soviet State and the schools, 1928-1939" Chapter 1: The cultural revolution and the crisis of Russian progressive education, 1927-April 1929 (Box 153, Folder 3)
        (including Hamison's review note)
    - Johnson, R.E. "Moscow workers and their families," 1973 (Box 153, Folder 4)
    - Kahan, Arcadius. "Soviet agricultural program: an evaluation of the 1965 goals," 1962 see Johnson, Gale
    - Kahk, Juhan; Remmel, Mart. "On investigation of agrarian development cycles by means of pattern recognition methods," 1981 (Box 153, Folder 5)
    - Kaminski, Andrzej. "Szlachta of the Polish-Lithuanian commonwealth and their government," 1983 (Box 153, Folder 5)
    - Keenan, Edward "Muscovy and Kazan: some introductory remarks on the patterns of steppe diplomacy," 1967 (Box 153, Folder 6)
    - Kemp-Welch, A. "Ideas of Nikolai Bukharin," 1992 (Box 153, Folder 6)
    - Kim, Alexander. "Soviet policy in Norht Korea," 1970 (Box 153, Folder 6)
    - Kirianov, Iu.I. "Svody otchetov fabrichnykh inspektorov" i drugie pravitel'stvennye (vedomstvennye) materialy kak istochnik izucheniia stachechnogo dvizheniia v Rossii v 1895-1916 gg." (Box 153, Folder 7)
    - Kline, George: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.2: General correspondence--Kline, George, Box 4, Folder 5
      - "In memory of a great philosopher: Edmund Husserl." Philosophy and Phenomenological Research: a Quarterly Journal, vol. XXII, No.4: 449-471, June 1962, (reprint) (Box 153, Folder 7)
        (inscribed by author to L.Haimson)
      - "Three Poems by Boris Pasternak." Russian Review, Vol. 21, No.3: 261-263, (reprint) (Box 153, Folder 7)
        (translation; inscribed by author to L.Haimson)
    - Koenker, Diane. "Strikes in revolution: Russia," 1917 (Box 153, Folder 8)
    - Koval'chenko, I.D. "Primenenie kolichestvennykh metodov i EVM v istoricheskikh issledovaniiakh" (Box 153, Folder 8)
    - Krasnova, V. "Polozhenie 19 fevralia 1861 g. i obrazovanie krest'ianskogo samoupravleniia," 1989 (Box 153, Folder 9)
    - Krieger, Leonard. "Autonomy of intellectual history," 1973 (Box 153, Folder 9)
    - Kulski, W.:
      - "1969 Moscow conference of communist parties," 1969 (Box 153, Folder 10)
      - "Politics and the Party: continuing revolution or new conservatism?" (Box 153, Folder 10)
      - "Soviet views of the German problem," 1969 (Box 153, Folder 10)
    - Kun, Joseph. 'North Korea: between Moscow and Peking," 1967 (Box 153, Folder 10)
    - Kucherov, Samuel. "Future of the Soviet collective farm," 1960 (Box 153, Folder 10)
    - Labelle, D. "Dmitrii Blagoev in Russia: an autobiographical letter," 1964 (Box 153, Folder 11)
    - LaFeber, Walter. "American historians and revolution," 1970 (Box 153, Folder 11)
    - Lagrange, Hugues. "Conjoncture economique et cycle des greves," 1982 (Box 153, Folder 11)
    - Lehman Papers (Box 153, Folder 12)
      (description)
    - Leiss, William. "Critical theory and its future," 1974 (Box 153, Folder 12)
    - Levin, Alfred. "Reactionary tradition in the election campaign to the Third Duma," 1962 (Box 153, Folder 13)
    - Levinton, Georgii. "K opisaniiu, interpretatsii i rekonstruktsii slavianskogo teksta so spetsializirovannoi pragmatikoi," 1975 (Box 153, Folder 13)
    - Lewis, Robert; Rowland, Richard. "Further investigation of urbanization and industrialization in pre-revolutionary Russia," 1974 (Box 153, Folder 13)
    - Liebich, Andre. "Marxism and totalitarianism: Rudolf Hilferding and the Mensheviks," 1986 (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - Lincoln, Bruce:
      - "Circle of the Grand Duchess Yelena Pavlovna," 1847-1861 (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - "Daily life of St. Petersburg official in the mid nineteenth century," 1975 (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - "God, the Emperor Nicholas I, and the revolution of 1848 a Young Rusian's fantasy account" (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - "Karlovka reform," 1970 (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - "Last years of the Nicholas "system": the unpublished diaries and memoirs of Baron Korf and General Tsimmerman," 1973 (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - "N.A.Miliutin and the St. Petersburg Municipal Act of 1846 a study in reform under Nicholas I," 1974 (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - "Genesis of an 'Enlightened' bureaucracy in Russia, 1825-1856," 1972 (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - "Profile of the Russian bureaucracy on the eve of the great reforms" (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - "Reform and reaction in Russia: A.V.Golovnin's critique of the 1860s," 1974 (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - "Russian state and its cities: a search for effective municipal government, 1786-1842," 1969 (Box 154, Folder 2)
    - Loeber, Dietrich:
      - "Legal rules "For internal use only", 1970 (Box 154, Folder 3)
      - "Problem of the Baltic gold in Great Britain," 1968 (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - Lubasz, Heinz. "Marx's initial problematic: the problem of poverty," 1976 (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - Ludz, Peter. "New Socialism": Philosophy in search of reality," 1969 (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - McDonald, David MacL. "Government and the origins of the Russo-Japanese war: Russian Far-East policy formation, 1892-1904," 1984 (Box 154, Folder 4)
    - McLean, Hugh:
      - "Et Resurrexerunt: how writers rise from the dead" (Box 154, Folder 5)
      - "Leskov and the Russian superman," 1968 (Box 154, Folder 5)
      - "Mikhail Zoshchenko. "Pered voskhodom solntsa," 1968 (book (Box 154, Folder 5)
        (review)
      - "Priest and the sorcerer: Leskov's first short story," 1967 (Box 154, Folder 5)
      - "Red virgin soil: Soviet literature in the 1920s. By Robert A. Maguire." 1969 (Box 154, Folder 5)
      - "To honor Roman Jakobson," 1967 (Box 154, Folder 5)
    - MacNaughton, Ruth. [Zemstvos] (Box 154, Folder 6)
    - Macey, David:
      - "Introduction to manuscript on Stolypin reforms" (Box 154, Folder 7)
      - "Reasantry, the agrarian problem, and the revolution of 1905-1907," 1971 (Box 154, Folder 7)
    - Manning Roberta. "Ideology of class struggle: the Russian nobility in transition 1905-1914," 1968 (Box 154, Folder 8)
    - Mayer, Arn:
      - "Internal causes and purposes of war in Europe, 1870-1956 a research assignment," 1969 (Box 154, Folder 9)
      - "Lower middle class as historical problem," 1975 (Box 154, Folder 9)
      - "On counterrevolution: a research assignment in contemporary European history, 1870-1956" (Box 154, Folder 9)
    - Melling, J. "Glasgow rent strikes and clydeside labour, 1914-15: the remaking of a working class?" (Box 154, Folder 10)
    - Menashe, Louis:
      - "Alexander Guchkov and the origins of the Octobrist Party: the Russian bourgeoisie in politics, 1905" (Box 154, Folder 11)
      - "How not to take Lenin seriously," 1970 (Box 154, Folder 11)
      - "Industrialists in politics Russia in 1905," 1968 (Box 154, Folder 11)
      - "Liberal with spurs": Alexander Guchkov, a Russian bourgeouis in politics," 1967 (Box 154, Folder 11)
    - Mihailovich, Vasa:
      - "Eerie world of Miodrag Bulatovic," 1968 (Box 154, Folder 12)
      - "Review essay: the critical reception of Anna Akhmatova" (Box 154, Folder 12)
    - Miller, Martin:
      - "Ideological conflicts in Russian populism: the revolutionary manifestoes of the Chaikovsky circle, 1869-1874" (Box 155, Folder 1)
      - "Origins of psychoanalysis in Russia before the 1917 revolution," 1986 (Box 155, Folder 1)
    - Monas, Sidney:
      - "Friends and enemies of the word," 1975 (Box 155, Folder 2)
      - "Leontiev: a Mediation," 1971 (Box 155, Folder 2)
    - Montgomery, David. "New Unionism" and the transformation of workers' consciousness in America, 1909-22," 1974 (Box 155, Folder 3)
    - Morris, David Morris. "Emergence of an industrial labor force in India: a study of the Bombay cotton mills, 1854-1947," 1965 (Box 155, Folder 3)
    - Moses, Russell:
      - "Freeing the hostages: the Carter administration, the Soviet Union and revolutionary Iran, 1979-1981" (Box 155, Folder 3)
      - "Soviet Union and the Second stage" (Box 155, Folder 3)
        (chapter)
    - Odom, William. "Party connection," 1973 (Box 155, Folder 4)
    - Olegina, I.N. 'Kapitalisticheskaia I sotsialisticheskaia industrializatsiia v traktovke A.Gershenkrona," 1971 (Box 155, Folder 4)
    - Ollman, Bertell. "Marx's use of "Class", 1968 (Box 155, Folder 4)
    - Owen, Thomas:
      - "Cooperation and conflict between tsarism and Russian capitalism, 1861-1914," 1982 (Box 155, Folder 5)
      - "Entrepreneurship and the structure of enterprise in Russia, 1800-1880," 1979 (Box 155, Folder 5)
      - "Founders of corporations in the Russian Empire, 1897" (Box 155, Folder 5)
        (list)
      - "System of English-language titles of business organizations in the Russian Empire, 1816-1913" (Box 155, Folder 5)
    - Paperno, Irina. "Myth of reality in N.G.Chernyshevsky's works and life" (Box 155, Folder 6)
    - Pinchuk, Ben-Cion. "Was there a Soviet policy for evacuation the Jews?: the case of the annexed territories," 1980 (Box 155, Folder 7)
    - Pintner, Walter:
      - "Russian higher civil service on the eve of the "Great Reforms", 1975 (Box 155, Folder 7)
      - "Social characteristics of the early nineteen-century Russian bureaucracy," 1970 (Box 155, Folder 7)
    - Pipes, Richard:
      - "Narodnichestvo: a semantic inquiry," 1964 (Box 155, Folder 8)
      - "Origins of Bolshevism: the intellectual evolution of young Lenin," 1968 (Box 155, Folder 8)
      - "Russian conservatism in the second half of the nineteenth century," 1970 (Box 155, Folder 8)
      - "Russian Marxism and its populist background: the late nineteenth century," 1960 (Box 155, Folder 8)
    - Pospielovsky, Dimitry. Story of a Phoenix: a study in re-awakening of Soviet society after Stalin's death, 1953-1974" (Box 155, Folder 9)
      (with related letters)
    - Procacci, Giuliano
      - "Communist International. 1919-1943 documents selected and edited by Jane Degras, "1958 (Box 155, Folder 10)
      - "Internazionale comunista dal I al VII Congresso, 1919-1935," 1958 (Box 155, Folder 10)
      - "Studi sulla Seconda Internazionale e sulla Socialdemocrazia tedesca," 1959 (Box 155, Folder 10)
    - Putnam, George. "P.B.Struve's view of the Russian revolution of 1905," 1967 (Box 155, Folder 10)
    - Rabinowitch, Alexander. "Heretical thoughts on the Bolsheviks and the October Revolution in Petrograd," 1974 (Box 155, Folder 11)
    - Ragionieri, Ernesto. "Archivalische forschungen zur geschichte der Deuschen arbeiterbewegung, veroffentlicht vom Institut fur Geschichte an der Deutschen Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin," 1958 (Box 155, Folder 11)
    - Raeff, Marc:
      - "150th anniversary of the campaign of 1812 in Soviet historical writing" (Box 155, Folder 12)
      - "Climat politique et les projects de reforme dans les premieres annees du Regne d'Alexandre I," 1961 (Box 155, Folder 12)
      - "Domestic policies of Peter III and his overthrow," 1970 (Box 155, Folder 12)